让我们快速看看连接几个
Let's just quickly look at what it looks like to concat a couple of
函子在一起。
functors together.
因此，如果我写了 Hello，请将它与世界数组连接起来。
So if I have a write of Hello, concat it with array of world.
我将有折叠日志 console.log 的行。
I shall have rows that fold log console.log.
我应该写一篇，否则我就会得到
I should have a write of or I will just get
你好世界，因为我正在折叠它。
hello world because I'm folding it out.
但它实际上是对 Hello world 的写入。
But what it is is actually a write of Hello world.
大家看到了吗？
Does everybody see that?
如果我还剩下 ahhhrgghghhhh 怎么办[笑]。
What if I have a left of ahhhrgghghhhh [LAUGH].
鉴于两者的行为，有人能猜到这里会发生什么吗？
Does anybody have a guess of what's gonna happen here given either's behaviour?
&gt;&gt; 左转。
&gt;&gt; Just to get a left.
&gt;&gt; 没错。
&gt;&gt; That's right.
它会使一切短路。
It will short circuit everything.
如果你在这个巨大的关联连接中的任何地方向左打，
If you hit a left anywhere in this giant associative concat,
如果我们要折叠一个巨大的左派或右派名单，那就是一堆以太。
if we're gonna fold a giant list of left's or rights a bunch of ethers.
如果你打左，
If you hit a left,
它只会将其作为错误返回，例如，我们有一个错误，我们最好告诉您。
it's just going to return that as an error like, we got an error we better tell you.
所以让我们看看。
So let's see that.
我得到了我们的。
I got our.
所以这很整洁。
So that's pretty neat.
我们可以用任务来做到这一点，对，你好任务
We can do this with task, right, task of Hello
猫的任务，残酷的世界。
cat task of, cruel world.
然后我们可以伪造它。
And then we can forge that.
然后我们仍然会并行进入，我们说我们有两个任务。
And then we'll still get in parallel in, we're saying we have two tasks.
他们都在奔跑，他们都将完成。
They're both running, they're both gonna finish.
他们都在做同步的事情，当你完成后，连接结果。
They're both doing a sync things and when you're done, concat the results.
如果我们把它放在一个数组中而不是连接字符串会怎样。
What if we put that in an array instead of concating the string.
您可以在任务内部连接数组，对吗？
You can concat the array inside the task, right?
所以这给了我们不同的行为。
So that gives us different behavior.
但它仍在连接，所以我们可以，我们有一个数组的权利，
But it's still concating and so then we can, we have a right of an array and
我们有一个左边或什么。
we have a left or whatever.
如果我们有一个被拒绝的任务。
If we have a rejected task.
拒绝，它的行为就像左。
Rejected, it acts like left.
因此，如果任何任务失败，哎呀，这些不是相同的数据类型，并且
So if any of the tasks fail, oops, these aren't the same data type and
这很好，因为这是一个不同的输出应该给你
that's fine because this is a different output should just give you
如果您有一个被拒绝的任务，任务上的错误。
the error on the task if you have a rejected task.
这样如果你在外面运行一堆同步的东西
So that way if you're out there running a bunch of a sync stuff and
其中一个失败了，你会得到它作为答案。
one of them fails, you'll get that back as the the answer.
它不会连接，非常像那里的左右行为。
It won't concat, so very much like right or left behavior there.
还有更多，但我想就此打住，对我们正在做的事情有任何疑问。
There's more but I want to stop here for any questions on what we're doing.
[笑]是的。
[LAUGH] yeah.
&gt;&gt; 这是相同的行为 promise.all，我们有一个
&gt;&gt; Is this the same behavior promise.all, where we have a single
链中的失败，结果只是，它被丢弃了。
failure in the chain and the result is just, it's discarded.
&gt;&gt; 没错，
&gt;&gt; That's right,
如果我们现在有一个失败，我们稍后会在这里讨论该怎么做。
if we have a single failure now, we'll talk about what to do here in a second.
我接下来会这样做。
I'll do that next.
如果我们想对此更宽容一点。
If we want to be a little bit more lenient on that.
但是，确实如此，这很有趣。
But, that is exactly and it's kind of interesting.
如果你考虑 promise.all，
If you think about promise.all,
你是说我有一堆在列表中运行的承诺。
you're saying I have a bunch of promises that are running in a list.
最后我真正想要的是，而不是一份承诺清单，
And really what I want at the end is, instead of a list of promises,
一个列表的承诺，我们可以从 traversable 的角度考虑它。
a promise of a list, and we can think of that in terms of traversable.
我们可以说就像在 Promise 之外翻转列表，反之亦然。
We could say like flip the list on the outside of the promise or vice versa.
然后我们开始，
And there we go,
我们在一个承诺中得到一堆结果，而不是一堆承诺的列表。
we get a bunch of results in one promise instead of a list of a bunch of promises.
在这里，我们是说，我想实际上折叠所有这些。
Here, we're saying, I want to actually fold all those down.
我想拿这份承诺清单
I wanna take this list of promises and
我想把它们都结合起来，效果完全一样。
I wanna combine them all and it's the same exact effect.
所以这里发生了什么，但它更强大一点，对吧？
So what's happening here is, but it's a little bit more powerful, right?
因为我们不只是要得到一个清单
Because we're not just gonna get a list and
我们将连接它们，但我们认为合适。
we're gonna concat them however we see fit.
所以你可以用单子来构建你的问题，几乎总是这样，就像
So you can frame your problem in terms of monads, almost always, it's like
最接近函数式编程中的灵丹妙药。
the closest thing to a silver bullet in functional programming as you can get.
引用 Chris Penner [笑]。
To quote Chris Penner [LAUGH].
所以让我们攻击这种情况，好吧，我正在编程。
So let's attack that case of, all right, I'm programming.
我要组合一堆东西。
I'm gonna combine a bunch of stuff.
当我合并时，我宁愿让我们看看，我们正在阅读一堆文件。
And while I'm combining, I would rather, let's see, we're reading a bunch of files.
以及我想要的所有文件，如果有一个丢失并且
And all my files I want to, if one is missing and
它炸了，我只想扔掉它，对吧？
it blows up, I just want to discard it, right?
所以我们可以说，
So we can say,
我们在这里尝试捕获返回读取文件同步或其他内容。
we have our try catch here that returns us the read file sync or whatever.
这将返回给我们一个右或左。
And this is gonna return us a right or left.
如果我正在阅读一大堆文件，我不希望它只是将它短路
And I don't want it to just short circuit it if I'm reading a whole bunch of files
我正在联系他们的所有内容，
and I'm concting all their contents,
如果我遇到错误，我不希望它只是停止。
I don't want it to just stop if I hit an error.
我只是想让它优雅而忘记它。
I just want it to be graceful and just forget about it.
那很优雅，但是，[笑] 忘记它。
That's graceful but, [LAUGH] forget about it.
所以让我们继续这样做。
So let's go ahead and do this.
让我们说，好吧，而不是与另一个权利结合或
Let's say, well, instead of right combining with another right or
左，你去给我左或买。
left, there you go and give me a left or buy.
我要去，我想保持权利。
I'm gonna, I want to keep the right.
所以我们可以通过几种不同的方式来做到这一点。
So we can do this a couple different ways.
有一个名为替代捕获选择的接口。
There's an interface called alternative the captures choice.
Mono 是捕获选择，对吧？
Mono is capture choice, right?
你可以说最大权是幺半群，你可以保留一个或
You can say maximum right is a monoid, where you can keep one or
另一个恒等式是无穷大或负无穷大。
the other identity being infinity or negative infinity.
但是替代接口的想法是我们要选择
But the idea of the interface of alternative is that we're gonna choose
这个或那个。
this or that one.
但是我们可以用半群来做这件事，或者说幺半群，让我们只是
But we can do this with semigroups by saying or monoids by saying, let's just
make，让我们把它包装成另一种类型，我们称之为替代品。
make, let's just wrap it in another type, let's call it alternative.
好的，所以我们有这个选择。
All right, so we have this alternative.
这将持有一个任一 x 而不仅仅是一个 x，好吧。
And this is gonna be holding an either x not just an x, all right.
宝石被称为 ex 以提醒我们，并且
The jewel is called ex to remind us, and
我们将通过说，好吧，好吧，让我们作弊。
we'll concat that by saying, all right, well, let's just cheat.
如果是左边，我知道他们在我的任何一个班级都有这个功能。
If it is the left, I know they have that function on my either class.
我们最终会保留另一个，或者我猜我们。
We will end up keeping the other one or I guess us.
因为如果我们离开了他们也离开了，
Because if we are left and they are left,
我们保留哪个左边真的没有关系，对吧？
it really doesn't matter which left we keep, right?
我们只保留第一个，所以跳过自己。
We're just gonna keep the first one, so skip ourselves.
那么，我们是否可以保留，哎呀，这是其他的。
So, are we, can keep, oops, this is other.
所以如果留下另一个，让我们保持自己，否则，
So if the other one is left, let's just keep ourselves otherwise,
我们要说让我们说
we're going to say let's say
ex.concat other.ex，把所有的都放到一个替代里面，对吧？
ex.concat other.ex, put that all into inside an alternative, right?
因为我们永远不能，它是关闭的，我们不应该在 concat 中逃脱。
Because we can't ever, it's closed, we shouldn't ever escape in a concat.
这是你应该做的第一件事。
That's the first thing you should do.
每当您准备好连接函数时，
Whenever you're ready to concat functions,
确保你没有脱离类型，因为那是错误，
make sure you're not falling out of the type, because that is error,
就像刚刚发生的事情。
like what just happened.
所以让我看看我的逻辑是否正确。
So let me see if my logic is correct.
如果我们这里还有剩余，我们会保留它。
If we've got a left over here, we're gonna keep it.
确实如此，我们要保住自己。
It does, we're gonna keep ourselves.
否则，我们将连接内部。
Otherwise, we're going to concat the insides.
现在我们实际上可以决定是否连接两者的内部或
Now we can actually decide whether or not to concat the insides of the two or
只保留外面的一个，对，我们可以保留第一个成功。
just keep the outer one, right, we can keep the first success.
所以这些是仍然满足界面的选择。
So these are choices that are still satisfy the interface.
但与这些函子幺半群的直觉一致，
But in keeping with the kind of intuition of these functor monoids,
我们要连接两者的内部。
we're gonna concat the insides of the two.
看看我是否做对了，我可能没有，如果有人看到任何问题，请大声说出来。
See if I get this right, I may not have, if anybody sees any problems shout it out.
我们离开了这个计划，这是任何人的猜测。
We got off the program it's a anybody's guess.
所以把这个 x 拿出来并折叠 ID，好吧。
So get this x out of there and folde ID, all right.
添加蓝色 where
Add by blue where
我们无法阅读是另一个。
we got can't read is left of the other one.
那是因为我在这里没有替代方案
That's because I don't have an alternative here, to alternative
好吧，那怎么样？
All right, so, how's that?
好的，所以它保持高，凉爽。
Okay, so it keeps the high, cool.
如果我用 concat an optional 连接这个替代方案怎么办？
What if I concat an alternative of this with concat an alternative?
又是一堆解释。
Another bunch of explanations.
现在用 by 连接它，嘿，做到了，对。
Now concat at that with the by, hey, did it, right.
所以每一个，
And so every,
它只是忽略了这里的左边，它没有，它什么都不做，这很好。
it just ignores the left here it doesn't, it doesn't do anything, which is nice.
所以如果我们利用这种级联嵌套
So if we're taking advantage of these kind of like this cascading kind of nesting,
一切都在那里，在嵌套的某个时刻，你可以说，你知道
where everything concats down, at some point in the nesting you can say, you know
什么，我不会继续向内连接并成为一个很好的嵌套公民。
what, I'm not going to continue to concat inward and be a nice nested citizen.
我将在这里做出决定并选择一个或
I'm going to make a decision here and choose one or
另一种分支我的代码有效。
the other kind of branch my code effectively.
或者我可以像我们在这里做的那样两者都做，
Or I can do both as we're doing here,
如果正确，我们只会连接内部。
we're only going to concat the inside if it's a right.
我想快速将其重写为折叠地图，然后我们将跳转
I want to rewrite this as a fold map real quick and then we'll jump
进入一些练习，我们会回来构建一个小的验证库。
into some exercises and we'll come back and build a little validation library.
但是，是的，所以我希望你在这里获得更多关于完整地图的经验。
But, yeah, so I want you to get some more experience with full map here.
事实证明，这是很多代码，对吧？
Turns out, this is a lot of code, right?
这有点烦人。
It's kind of annoying.
所以我们可以做的是，我将继续并将其放入列表中。
So what we could do is, I'm gonna go ahead and put this into a list.
他们让我的清单不是从一开始就得到的，只是导入它，好吗？
They have my list don't get from the first thing and just import it, okay?
所以我们会有一个嗨的列表。
So we'll have a list of Hi.
还有怎么会
And how would
只是a，b，c。
just a, b,c.
我们要做的是把那些我猜我们做不到的。
And what we're gonna do is put those I guess we can't do that.
我们必须做对a，对b，
We have to do a right a, right b,
和 c 的右边，好吧，c 的左边。
and a right of c, okay, left of c.
现在我们将继续将Map 折叠成替代和
And now we'll just go ahead and foldMap into alternative and
我们可以像reduce一样选择忽略初始值。
we can choose just like reduce to ignore the initial value.
但通常在调用站点，您知道初始值是什么。
But oftentimes at the calling site, you know what the initial value is.
所以你想保证它的安全并提供初始值。
So you want to keep it safe and provide initial value.
所以我的初始值，
So my initial value,
如果我有一堆字符串，我的空元素就是一个空字符串。
if I have a bunch of strings my empty element is an empty string.
要么我的空元素是对的，要么
And either my empty element is a right and or
我想我的中立然后另类持有。
I guess my neutral and then alternative holding that.
所以我们将把所有这些地图折叠成一个替代品
So we'll fold map all these into an alternative and
那么希望这会奏效。
then hopefully this will work.
我们得到了 a 和 b，它连接了内部，万岁。
And we got a and b, it concats the insides, hooray.
有用。
It works.
如果我把它留在这里，我们会得到 a 和 c。
If I make this left here, we'll get a and c.
所以你最终实际上会制作你自己的幺半群。
So you'll end up actually making your own monoids quite a bit.
但这个想法是你最终会制作自己的幺半群
But the idea is that you'll end up making your own monoids
比你要制作自己的粉丝等等要多得多。
a lot more than you are gonna make your own fanctors and such.
所以，知道如何制作这些东西是很好的。
So there, it's good to know how to make these things.
当然，你可以通过一堂课来做到这一点。
And of course you can make it with a class.
你不必在这些小功能中做到，
You don't have to make it in these little functions,
你可以让它更有效率或其他什么。
you can make it more efficient or whatever.
有十几种方法可以做到。
There's a dozen ways to do it.
好的，让我们去。
Okay, so let's go to.
&gt;&gt; 按照你的模式，你会像 MD 一样，那是对的吗？
&gt;&gt; Following your pattern you would make like an MD and that would be a right?
&gt;&gt; 那，是的，你会创建一个，如果你想制作一个幺半群，你必须有 concat。
&gt;&gt; That, yeah, you'd create a, if you want to make a monoid you have to have concat.
而对于半群，
And for semigroup,
你只需要定义一个 concat 方法 empty 就像一个类方法，通常，
you just have to define a concat method empty is like a class method usually,
因为如果它是那个类的一个实例，为什么你会有一个实例。
because why would you have an instance if it is an instance of that class.
所以通常这就是为什么我在类本身上放空的原因。
So usually that's why I'm kind of putting empty on the class itself.
这样它就给了我任何东西的初始价值。
So that way it gives me my initial value of whatever.
所以我们走了。
So there we go.